

Vaskar Chakma

Date of birth: 06/02/2001 | **Nationality:** Bangladeshi | **Gender:** Male

Phone number: (+86) 17505222809 (Mobile) | Email address:

vaskarchakma@stmail.ntu.edu.cn | **Website:** https://vaskarchakma.github.io/ |

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/home.vaskar | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vaskar-chakma/ | **WeChat:** VaskarChakma |

Skype: vaskarchakma7@gmail.com

Address: Headmen Para, 1 no word, Rangamati Main Post Office, Kotwali,

Rangamati., 4500, Rangamati, Bangladesh (Home)

Address: Nantong University, SeYuan Campus, SeYuan No 9 Road., 226019,

NANTONG, China (Study)

ABOUT ME

From a Boy to a Man, being raised in a marginalized Chakma community currently enrolled at Nantong University as an Undergrad student of Computer Science.

Open to higher studies and research opportunities. My research interests are *Machine learning*, *Artificial Intelligence*, and *Cyber Security*. Besides, I like to travel. I believe traveling gives you a new perspective on everything. You get to know a lot about the different cultures, the cuisines, their history, the language and all the small unique things every place has to offer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

23/09/2023 - CURRENT Nantong, China

STUDENT VOLUNTEER NANTONG UNIVERSITY

Managing newly admitted international students who came from different countries. Helping them check in to the university, check their documentation, and report to the School of International Education (SIE), NTU, etc.

Address Nantong University, SeYuan Campus, SeYuan No 9 Road., 226019, Nantong, China

13/08/2021 - CURRENT Rangamati, Bangladesh

HEAD OF HUMAN RESOURCES DEVELOPMENT WING RHUVAGA

- 1. Leadership
- 2. Communications
- 3. Public dealing
- 4. Team work
- 5. Project management
- 6. Public speaking

04/03/2021 - 20/01/2023 Rangamati, Bangladesh

DISTRICT AMBASSADOR BLUE TEAM BANGLADESH LTD.

- 1. Team Work
- 2. Learning Cyber Security
- 3. Penetration Testing

16/08/2017 - 30/12/2020 Rangamati, Bangladesh

RED CRESCENT YOUTH VOLUNTEER BANGLADESH RED CRESSCENT SOCIETY

- 1. To help those who suffer,
- 2. Without discrimination,

- 3. Whether during the conflict,
- 4. In response to natural or man-made disasters or due to conditions of chronic poverty.

Business or Sector Administrative and support service activities

Address K K Royy Street, Rangamati Main Post Office, Kotwali, Rangamati., 4500, Rangamati, Bangladesh

Email rangamati@bdrcs.org | Website www.bdrcs.org

Link https://drive.google.com/file/d/1nYVnz8j8XWkg_t0Ur7kClD8bd231fvDW/view?usp=sharing

06/01/2007 - 26/05/2008 Dighinala, Bangladesh

SCOUT LEADER BANGLADESH SCOUTS

- 1. Caring or working with young people
- 2. Managing or raising money
- 3. Sharing skills with others
- 4. Communications, media, or publicity
- 5. Learning skills in different ways

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

15/09/2021 - CURRENT Nantong, China

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE Nantong University

Address No- 9, Seyuan Road, Nantong, Jiangsu, China., 226019, Nantong, China | Website http://sie.ntu.edu.cn/ |

Field of study Computer Science and Technology

20/11/2023 - 25/11/2023 United States

AUTOMATE CYBERSECURITY TASKS WITH PYTHON Google and Coursera

Website https://www.coursera.org/ | Field of study Database and network design and administration

Link https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/WK2WRW9YGRNX

Dhaka, Bangladesh

HOUR OF CODE U.S. Embassy Bangladesh & Arduino Community Bangladesh

Website https://bd.usembassy.gov/ | Field of study Software and applications development and analysis

Link https://drive.google.com/file/d/1pSH0jaYs7H7flQa7z_K5ZVieHXXsrjxa/view?usp=sharing

13/02/2022

ETHICAL HACKING: COMPLETE NMAP COURSE | PROJECT BASE Udemy

Website https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-40915612-141b-4c12-aca6-36a92a09c6da/

07/08/2021 United States

PROTECT AGAINST SECURITY THREATS ON AZURE Microsoft

Website https://learn.microsoft.com/ | Field of study Information and Communication Technologies

 $\label{linkhamma} \textbf{Link} \ \underline{\text{https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/training/achievements/learn.azure.protect-against-security-threats-azure.badge?username=VaskarChakma-1649\&sharingId=4C33B906947E29DC}$

31/01/2022 - CURRENT Bangladesh

PROBLEM SOLVING (BASIC) HackerRank

Website https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/eadf59aa54a0

SECURITY IN EMERGENCIES International Committee of the Red Cross - ICRC

Website www.ifrc.org | Field of study Health and welfare

Link https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Xq6Tcsbt1hnmDYDP-IMX5Xw7-M5ALa-E/view?usp=sharing

07/2021 Bangladesh

VOLUNTEERISM FOR SOCIAL CHANGE Bangladesh Youth Leadership Center (BYLC)

Website https://bylc.org/ | Field of study Personal skills and development

Link https://x.bylc.org/slides/volunteerism-for-social-change-105

2022 Rangamati, Bangladesh

DIGITAL KHICHURI CHALLENGE United Nations Development Programme, Bangladesh

Address Moanoghar Residential School, Rangamati Main Post Office, Kotwali, Rangamati., 4500, Rangamati, Bangladesh

Field of study Inter-disciplinary programmes and qualifications involving Information and Communication Technologies (ICTs)

Link https://drive.google.com/file/d/10eb00ycE0VudANo BJSPrl9dXtpj3Jwd/view?usp=sharing

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): CHAKMA

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
BENGALI	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
ENGLISH	B2	B2	B2	В2	B2
CHINESE	B2	B2	B1	B1	A2
HINDI	B1	B1	A2	A2	B1
URDU	B1	A1	A2	A2	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Python Programming | CYBER SECURITY | C/C++ Programming | Web Development + Web Design | Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel) | SEO | Google (Google Meet, Google Docs, Google Classroom, Google Forms, Google Drive, Google Slides)